The Busher’s Welcome Home

on the Ship bord. Feb. 6.

Friend Al: Well Al here we are in the Meadow Training ocean and this is the last day we will be on the Ship bord till we get to London Eng. and from now till we get a bord of the boat at London for N.Y. City we will all the wile be on land in Itly Rome Paris France and so 4th. Wear do in Naples tommorow and thats the 1st place we stop at wile wear in Itly and we stay there 3 days with out playing no ball game so they wont be no chanct for me to find out if my scarab is going to bring me luck or not going to bring me no luck.

Talking a bout my scarab and that reminds me what come off yest. and last night and theys some stiffs a long on the trip that you couldent get them to stoop to low and that they isent nothing they wouldent do even steal and I ain’t found it out who done it yet or that is tride to do it but who ever was it would steal candy a way from a blind man wile there back was turned and when I find out who was it Im going to tell Comiskey and Callahan and they will see what kind of a gang of theifs they brot a long on the trip.

I guess I told you a bout me geting a hold of that scarab in Cairo and it was a big bargun because the man that sold it to me wouldent of never gave it up only it wasent hisn and he was hard up and this is a genuwind scarab from the tume of Cops that was the cheif of Police in Cairo 4 thousend yrs. a go & I give the man $7.50 for it and Steve Evans says its the gratest bargun a man ever got because 1 of these here scarabs if there genuwind gives you nothing but good luck and you cant have no bad luck as long is you carry them a round with you.

Well yest. p.m. we was setting out on the porch I and Evans and Schaefer and a hole bunch of us and Schaefer halled some thing out of his pockit and it was a bout 10 of these here scarabs only of coarse not the real scarabs but fakes and some body ast him how much did he give for them and he says a nichol a peace and then he says to me Do you want to buy 1 of them off of me so as you will get some luck and I says No. I dont want no fake scarab because I got a real 1 and Schaefer says how much did you give for it and I says $7.50 and Schaefer says leave me see it a minut and I says Yes if you will promus to give it back right a way so he give me his promus and I halled out my scarab and showed it to them and they all says it was a dandy.

Then Schaefer put my scarab in his hand a long with his fake scarabs and then he held his hand out and ast me to pick my scarab out and at 1st they all of them looked pretty near a like and I dident know for a minut witch was mine but Evans says Cant you tell a real scarab from a fake and then he picked mine right out of the bunch with out no trubble and then he says You should ought to be a shamed of your self not knowing a real scarab from a fake and if you aint care full some body will get yours a way from you and you will be carring a fake a round in your pockit and wundring why dont you get some luck so I says How do you tell them a like and he says You cant tell by just looking with out a hole lot of practice but if you get a hold of them you can tell OK because you can bite on them and if its a real scarab it dont make no noise but if there a fake they sqeek like a rat.

So then he give me my scarab and I bit on it and they wasent no noise of any kind. But Schaefer was jellus a bout me haveing a real 1 and him haveing a lot of fakes so he beggin talking like hisn was as good is mine so I says all right think so if you want to but wait and see witch 1 of us has the luck.

Well Al when I come to bed last night I herd a noise like some body trying to get in to my birth room and at 1st I was going to jump up and open the door and smash who ever was it jaw and then I thot I better just lay there and leave them open the door and come in and then I would have them where they couldent get a way but they couldent open the door so pretty soon I dident hear no noise no more so I got up and went to the door and they was gone so this a.m. I told Evans a bout it and he says it was probily some body after my scarab and if he was me he wouldent carry it a round with me but get the perser to stick it in the safe so now its in the safe and if some body steals it out of there the peopl that owns the boat will half to come acrost but I guess they wouldent of no body tride to steal my scarab if it wasent a real 1 and I ast Schaefer this a.m. was they any body tride to steal hisn and he says no so that prooves whose got the real scarab and whose got the fakes.

But it shows you what a fine gang we got a long on the trip and pertending like wear all pals to gather but the minut your backs turned they would steal your shirt and I guess some of these here pitchers would like to steal my fast ball but if they did they wouldent have nothing only a fast ball because they aint got nothing there self but I guess if they had my fast ball they wouldent need nothing else hey Al.

Well Al we get to Naples tommorow night and I will male you this letter from there and they should ought to be some male waiting for me there from Florrie and little Al and of coarse I dont mean that little Al will be writeing me a letter but Florrie would know better then write me a letter and not say nothing a bout him and Im crazy to know how is he geting a long talking yet and how much does he weigh and so 4th and he should ought to have sevrel teeth by this time but I guess I shouldent be in no hurry for him to get a jaw full of teeth and that means all the sooner I would half to be buying stake for him.

Your old Pal.
Jack.

Naples, It. Feb. 8.

Friend Al: Well Al tommorow we will be threw with Naples and wear going to Rome next and I hope Romes a lifer place then Naples and all as we been doing for 2 days is looking at this in that and the other thing diffrunt mts. and Vilecanose and bldgs. and so 4th and Im tireder then if Id pitched 2 double headers in 1 p.m. tho I guess I could do that all right when my arm feels good because when a mans got a fast ball like mine you dont hardily ever half to use your curve and when my arms good I could zip them fast ones threw there all day and not never feel it.

Well Al they wasent no male for me here not even a post card and I dont know weather little Als a live or dead and burred and how would you like to have a wife that dont never have time to write to you tho of coarse they wouldent be no sence in Bertha writeing to you when you dont never go a way no wheres or Bertha nether and besides you havent got no baby and Bertha wouldent have nothing to write a bout even if she went a way some wheres and set down to write you a letter.

We got here yest. and the 1st thing when we land it they was a Dr. come a round and exxamined us to see weather we had any thing and Evans says to him Dont waist your time exxamineing the pitchers because they aint none of them got nothing and he ment that we was all big helthy fellows tho of coarse they aint all of us that way and theys 1 or 2 of them that could take on a few lbs. with out crowding no body off of the bench. And then we was drove to the hotel and Callahan says we could go any wheres we wanted and I wanted to go up in my room and lay down but the boys says it wouldent be no fun going any wheres with out me so I had to go a long and we went and seen Pump A and Linoleum and Mt. Vesuvius and Evans says it was a good thing we got vaxinated up to japan so as we wouldent be in no danger if old Vesuvius had a erupsion and hes all ways pulling off stuff like that.

This is Sun. and I dident go no wheres accept to see some of the mts. and runes we dident see yest. and if they hadent of told me these was diffrunt I would of thot they was the same and Im glad it dident cost me nothing to see them and a little wile a go we was all called to gather and a wop give us a couple of bronx statues 1 for the giants and 1 for the White Sox and there statues of athaletes and the 1 the giants got is a left hander and it looks like he had just let lose of the ball and hes looking out to right field probily to see where the batters going to hit it and if hes like most of the left handers he will half to go and clime up on the right field fence if he wants to see the ball lite, and the 1 Comiskey got is an other athalete geting ready to throw a plate at some body and probily him and his Mrs. has had a quarl but you cant tell because the statue dont say nothing on it and both the statues is bear and not a stich of cloths on them and I guess theyd be bigger crowds come to the ball games if we drest like that hey Al tho theys all ways a pretty fare crowd out to the south side park in Chi when its my turn to work.

I ment they wasent nothing wrote on the statues to tell you who they are but theys a motto wrote on them both and the mottos was wrote by Hal Cane and Evans says hes wrote a lot of grate books some of them pretty near as long is the Bibble.

Well Al Comiskey wont half to keep his statue locked up in no safe because I wont try and steal it off of him and take it home because evry time we had Co. we would half to rap it up in a over coat or some thing.

Well Al I will try and write you a letter wile wear in Rome and we will be home a bout 1 mo. from today.

Your pal.
Jack.

Rome, It. Feb. 13.

Old Pal: Well Al they could of left this burg off of the skedule and I wouldent of made no holler and they should ought to call it rain insted of Rome and they dident give us no rooms with a bath in the hotel where wear stopping at but Schaefer says they dident bild no bath rms. in the hotels here because when the hotels was bilt all the peopl drest like them statues and when they wanted a bath all as they had to do was go out and stand on the side walk in the rain but now the police has made them ware cloths so they half to get a long with sparrow baths in the wash bold.

Well Al Im so sick in tired of staying in the hotel and nothing to do that I couldent stand it laying a round here an other day and I would jump out the window or some thing but wear going to Niece tonight.

May be thats a lifer place than this is and the sun shins onct in a wile.

We could may be of played a game the day we got here 3 days a go because it wasent raining then but just geting ready to rain but the mare of the town says No base ball was to ruff and wouldent leave us play so Callahan and Mcgraw had to get out and show him what the games like and I guess he thot it was foot ball or some thing or may be he thot the pitcher shot the ball out of a canon and tride to hit the batter and I guess if he could see my fast ball when my supers good he would think the ball was shot out of a canon but any way when Mcgraw and Callahan explaned the game to him he seen they wasent nothing ruff a bout it so he says we could play the next day and then it beggin to rain and been raining ever sence and dont look like it was in no hurry to stop.

So theys been nothing doing and no chanct to see if my scarabs going to bring me luck. Some of the boys has been out looking at more runes and wanted I should go a long but I told them I guest I could live a few yrs. with out seen no more runes and the day before yest. they was all up calling on the pope & wanted I should go a long but you had to ware your evening cloths and it just ment getting them soked and the boys that went has got some runes of there own to look at now I mean there evening cloths that they wore out in the rain. But I guess I should ought to of went a long at that because Evans says the pope ast where I was and Evans had to tell him I was sick and Evans says its bad enough to lie to any body let a lone the pope.

Well Al I and Schaefer was talking a bout the rotten weather and Schaefer says he was talking a bout it with some of the peopl that lives here and they told him this was the worst rain sence the rain of Nearo and they use to have a lot worse rains then they have now and they got all the diffrunt rains named like the rain of Cesar the rain of August S. and so 4th and its a fine burg Al where they got so much rain that they half to name the diffrunt rains to tell them a part and if this burg was in the league theyd play on the home grounds a bout twict a yr. and on them 2 days theyd half to start a bout 1 a clock in the a.m. to get in all the double headers and probily the grounds would be 5 or 6 ft. under water and take a little sod off like Bush or Schalk and theyd half to come up evry little wile and get some air and the outfielders would probily half to ride a round in boats and at that I bet I could take a mud skow and get a round as fast is some of them outfielders with out menshoning no bodys name.

Well Al wear leaveing right after supper tonight and the sooner we get a way from here I will be tickeled to deth.

Your pal.
Jack.

Niece, It. Feb. 16.

Friend Al: Well old Pal I guess the scarabs OK and I dident get stung when I bought it and its ½ payed for it self all ready and then some. They was a game this p.m. the 1st game we played sence we come a way from Cairo but it wasent in the game where I found out a bout the scarab being OK because Mcgraw wouldent leave me pitch the game because he is saveing me for the day after tommorow in Paris when they will be a big crowd. The giants got beat this p.m. 10 to 9 and they wasent none of the pitchers had a thing and I could of went in there and throwed left hand it and give the both sides a triming but Mcgraw says he dident care nothing a bout this game and the 1st game in Paris is the 1 he wants to win and thats why he kept me on the bench and wouldent take no chanct of wareing me out.

But I was going to tell you a bout the scarab and what it done for me and heres what it done for me Al. We went over to monte Carlo a hole gang of us and thats the place where they run all them gamboling games faro and chuckle luck and the roll it wheel where you bet what coller the marbles going to drop in to or you can pick a No. and bet on that only of coarse theys so many Nos. that a mans a sucker to try and pick out any 1 No. but theys only 2 collers and you can bet weather its going to be black or red.

Well Al before we start it out Evans ast me did I have my scarab a long and I says no so he made me go back and get it and I kept it in my pants pockit all the wile we was over there and they was a big crowd a round the diffrunt tables but I and Evans found a place and I dident make no bets for a wile and he made a few and dident win none of them because he was trying to pick out a No. so finely I layed down a $1 only they call it 5 franks here and in Itly it would be 5 liars and I layed it down on the red and sure enough up come the red and the cooper give me an other dollar so I says I was threw but Evans says I better try it again and bet the both of my $1 at onct but I wasent no sucker like that so I stuck a $1 in my pockit and bet the other $1 on the red and sure enough it come red again and the cooper had to give me an other $1.

So Evans says now your playing with there money why dont you bet the hole $2 at onct so I seen where I wouldent be nothing out if I lost it so I bet the hole $2 on the red and sure enough it come up red so then I says Im threw and Evans says he wouldent never be threw as long is the luck was staying with me like that and he wanted I should play the hole $4.00 that Id all ready win on the red but I says no and wile we was argueing a bout it they throwed the marble again and it come up black so you see Al I would of lost the hole $4 if Id did what Evans wanted I should so I give him the laugh and I got up and left the table and he come with me and we went and found the other boys and they was all looseing there money as fast is they played it trying to pick out Nos. insted of collers so Evans told them what Id pulled off and Scott wanted me to sell the scarab to him and says he would give me $10.00 for it and I give him the laugh and now you see Al that the scarabs only costed me $3.50 insted of $7.50 because it win $4.00 for me playing roll it and after we come out of the place Evans says he over herd the prop. say that he was glad I wasent going to stay no longer because the way things was brakeing for me I would probily have all there money in a couple hrs.

And Scott says 1 of the coopers ast him if I dident have some luck peace in my pockit because he never seen no body win 3 bets in suceshon before and Scott told him no that I was just born lucky because theys a rule against carring scarabs in there when your going to play the wheel and they would of tooken my money a way from me if they had of found out a bout me haveing a scarab but they wont get the money now because I got it right here and the scarabs hid a way where they couldent find it. O you little scarab hey Al.

Theys a big st. carnval going on here and evry body drest up yest. and parade it up and down the sts. in funny customs and we all put on our base ball sutes and road in the parade and I guess its a good thing Florrie wasent a round Al the way some of them girls over looked me and theys some fine looking girls a round here but of coarse I got a wife now and dont have nothing to do with no pretty girl.

Well Al we go to Paris tommorow and I will may be write you a letter from there.

Your old pal.
Jack.

Paris. Feb. 21.

Al: Well Al this place is worse then Rome when it comes to rain and the 1st day we was in Rome it dident rain but they hasent been no day like that here and they wasent no more chanct to play a game here then a man could fly you might say but it can rain all the rest of the winter and I wont have no holler comeing because I dont half to pitch no ball game now to find out weather my scarabs lucky because I found out now for sure Al and I dont mean a bout me wining that money at monte Carlo but I got an other big peace of news for you but probily you will see it in the Chi papers before you get this letter and may be you all ready know a bout it but theys a chanct that the federals wants to keep it a secrit for a wile and pull it just before the season opens up. So I will tell you a bout it Al and you can see for your self weather the scarab brot me luck.

Well Al I wont be with the White Sox this comeing season but I will be with the federal and geting what Im worth and Comiskey and Callahan can jump in Mich. lake as far as Im conserned and the White Sox to and I will be pitching for the Chicago federal and I bet Comiskey will wisht he had of gave me real money when he finds out his pitching staff is all shot to peace is and probily ½ the peopl thats been going to the White Sox pk. will quite going there and come over where the federals plays there games and the federals is going after all the stars and they will get them to because they aint afrade to let lose of there money.

Well Al I will tell you how it come off and I and Schaefer and Evans was setting in the hotel this a.m. and Schaefer says Well boys we made a big miss take leaveing home this winter and Evans says how is that and Schaefer says the federals was sineing up all the stars that stayed home and giveing them grate big salerys and Cobb and Mathewson and Lajoie and Jackson and a hole lot others had all ready jump to the federal and probily we would of got them offers if we had of been where they could get a hold of us. So Evans says Well they could get a hold of us all right if they wanted to because they could wire us a telegram couldent they and Schaefer says Yes but may be there afrade that Callahan or Comiskey or Mcgraw would get a hold of the telegrams and not give them to us and then Evans says Thats right and I wouldent be supprised if some telegrams had all ready came for some of us and Comiskey and Mcgraw was holding them out on us so Schaefer says I bet thats the dope and Im going up and ast the clerk if they was any telegrams come for me that some body else got a hold of them.

So Schaefer left us and went up to the dest and talked to the clerk a wile and pretty soon he come back and says nothing doing and we hadent set there more then 5 minuts after he come back when all of a sudden 1 of the bell hops come a round yelling my name and I ast him what was it and he says they was a cable for me only he says it in France and Evans had to tell me what was he saying so he give me the cable telegram and I couldent hardily open it Al because I thot sure it was from Florrie and may be little Al was sick or dead or some thing but after a wile I got it opened up and it wasent from Florrie a tall Al but Joe Tinker the mgr. of the Chi federal and it says Jack Keefe St. Jas. hotel Will give you ten thousend dollars per anum 3 yr. contrack to pitch for us cable the anser at onct and then it was sined Joe Tinker.

Well Al you could of knock me down with a toy bloom only at 1st I thot it was a joke or some thing but then I seen it was wrote on the reglar paper like they all ways send telegrams on it so I seen it wasent no fake so I just set there and couldent say nothing and finely Evans says Whats the matter bad news and I says Well I wouldent hardily call it bad news and then I showed he and Schaefer the telegram and I thot theyd brake my arm off shakeing hands with me and pounding me on the back and Evans says You lucky stiff and I says How a bout that little scarab now and Evans says Yes and who got that scarab for you and you should ought to come acrost because if it hadent of been for me you wouldent of never saw the scarab so I says All right I aint no Sherlock and I will buy the ciggars for the both of you and Evans says Yes you should ought to buy a man 2 ciggars for geting you 10 thousend per anum so I says all right you cant call me no piker so I took them out and bought a couple ciggars for Evans and 1 for Schaefer and I wasent going to give Schaefer no 2 ciggars when he dident have nothing to do with me geting a hold of the scarab and he was lucky to get 1 ciggar.

So then Evans says Well you better hurry up and anser the telegram or may be Tinker will change his mind and take the offer back so I ast them what to put in the anser and they says what I should put in it just Except your offer and will sine as soon is I get home and then they both of them wanted I should put some thing in a bout them and ast Tinker if he dident have no jobs for them so I stuck that in to and then I went in the telegram ofice and tride to send the telegram but they wouldent send it unlest I payed for it 1st so I says how much is it and they says 31 cts a word and what do you think of that for a robbers game Al but they wasent no use makeing a holler because I couldent take no chanct of Tinker changeing his mind so I give them the money and it was $3.72 all to gather because I cut out the part a bout Evans and Schaefer because Tinker will let them know if he wants them and may be he dont want them and its none of my busness weather he wants them or not.

So then I thot I better tell Callahan a bout it but Schaefer and Evans told me I better not because may be the federal might blow up before the season start it and then I wouldent have no job no wheres so I aint going to say nothing to ether he or Comiskey for a wile tho I guess they aint no chanct of the federal blown up when they got all them stars sined up and all that money to spend hey Al and I hope Tinkers got Cobb sined up for his club and I guess that wouldent be some comebination hey Al with Cobb geting the runs and me makeing the other club look like a sucker and I guess Cobb would be tickeled to deth to be on the same club with me because then he wouldent never half to hit against me accept in practice onct in a wile and I can make him look like a sucker on my curve ball any time he steps up there. Well Al if Tinkers got Cobb we will go threw that federal league like soup threw a sift and it will be a shame to take the money. O you 10 thousend per anum.

Well Al thats the bigest news I got to tell you and if it aint in the papers youll be the 1st 1 to know a bout it out side of I and Tinker and Evans and Schaefer because I aint going to tell Florrie nothing a bout it till we get home and then I will spring it on her for a supprise. Some supprise party hey Al.

Well the boys has all been a round Paris seen the sites and theys plenty to see but Im all tired out with it all ready and cant hardily wait till we get to London and get on the bord of the Ship for home and I guess I wont only pitch 1 more game on the trip and that will be in London and may be that will be the last time I ever pitch with Callahan looking at me but its his own falt him and Comiskey and if they had of gave me a real salery in the 1st place I wouldent half to jump to the federal to get the money.

Well Al we seen all they was to see a round here and seen the place where Lajoies grate granfathers burred and the diffrunt liberys and gallerys and so 4th and Im glad Florrie dident come a long on the trip because the wommen in the party has been spending all there time in the diffrunt stores buying hats and cloths and some of them will have enough diffrunt cloths so as they can ware a diffrunt dress out to the ball pk. evry day and go home and change between the 2 games when theys a double header. And we was gave a dinner party by a man that makes champlain wine and of coarse they was nothing to do but I must write 1 of them pones of mine and talk it off at the party and heres what I give them Al:

Well boys wear all sorry
We couldent give you no game.
But you dident give us no good weather
Rain rain rain.

I wisht I could of pitched a game here
It would of gave me plesure
but I guess the White Sox are all
Of them glad it was rotten weather.

Well boys wear on our way home
From the trip a round the world
And soon we will be in america
The Home of the U.S.A.

But we wont for get you boys
You showed us all the sites
so hurrah for Paris the best place in the world
Accept the stars and strips.

Well Al I got to do some packing because wear leaveing here tommorow a.m. for London and I will write you an other letter in London and I bet your tickeled to deth over the good news Ive gave you Al and I know I would be tickeled to deth to hear a bout you landing a good job only of coarse it wouldent be no 10 thousend per anum. O you 10 thousend per anum. Hey Al.

Your old pal.
Jack.

London. Eng. Feb. 27.

Al: Well Al it takes more then a scarab for a man to be lucky is some of these lucky stiffs and some of them must of been born with a silver horse shoe in there mouth the lucky stiffs and all as they half to do is throw there bat at a ball and make base hits when they got there eyes shut and if I was as lucky is some of them stiffs I would quite playing ball and buy stock in 1 of these here gold minds and theyd probily find dimonds and insted of them finding gold theyd probily find dimonds or some thing.

Well Al I guess Ive pitched my last game for Callahan and of coarse I wasent pitching for Callahan but Mcgraw but I wont do no more pitching where Callahans watching me because I will be in the federal as soon is we get home where he cant see me no more and I would of gave a $100.00 to of win this game on acct. of it being the last game I pitched with Callahan watching me but I guess he seen that they was lucky to beat me and a man cant win no game no matter how much stuff you got when your working against a club thats so lucky that if they got a hold of some stock in a gold mind some wheres theyd probily be dimonds insted of gold.

This here Daly should ought to start a black Smith shop with them horse shoes hes got and the White Sox sined him for a catcher but hes been playing 1 base on this trip on acct. of Callahan not haveing no reglar 1 base man a long on the trip so Daly was lucky to be in the game let a lone brake it up with a base hit and as soon is we get home youll read a bout him geting sent back to the new Eng. league and Im glad I dont half to pitch in that league if there all as lucky is him.

Well old pal I wasent feeling nothing like my self any way and how could a man feel right when you been laying a round this burg 3 or 4 days and the air damp and fogy all the wile and yest. was the 1st time we seen the sun sence we got here so my arm was lame and stiff and I wouldent of never went in there only king Geo. the king of Eng. and the Lord mare of London and all the other High puloy was out to the game and Mcgraw dident dast pitch no body else only me on acct. of them peopl being out to the game and expected to see the best we had to show them. So when Mcgraw says I was to work I dident say nothing back a bout me not feeling good so before the game he dident know nothing a bout how bad I felt but if he was any kind of a mgr. he would of saw the minut I went in there that I wasent right and tooken me out. Or may be he seen they was something the matter with me but was afrade to take me out on acct. of may be the peopl that come to the game would make a holler.

Well any way I went in there and the ball felt like it wade a 100 lbs. and I couldent do nothing with it and couldent hardily raze my arm a bove my solder and evry ball I throwed pretty near killed me but I wasent going to say nothing as long is Mcgraw insist it I should pitch so I stuck it out and I would of beat them at that if theyd been some body behind me besides a bunch of lofers that all there thinking a bout is get home and win an other penant in the Nat. league and get the loosers share of the serious money and they should ought to thank them self that there in the Nat. league and if they was in the american league they would be giveing the st. Louis club and the yankees a tuft battle.

Well they played like a bunch of these here collige willy boys and they should ought to of murdered what Benz was sloping up there but they act it like they was a scarred may be they would hit a hard foul and the ball would go threw the scream and hurt king Geo. and they would get arested for a trader so when we come up to the 10 ining the score was tide 4 and 4 and 2 out and up come this here lucky busher Daly and I was waisting my curve ball right a long on acct. I couldent get no brake to it because the ball was heavy and logy so I waisted a curve ball on him and he throwed his bat at it and catched it just right and made a home run off of it and that wounded the game up and we was licked and all the willy boys in the grand stand claped there hands and made Daly think he was a grate guy when he should ought to of been arested for ever swinging at the ball and pretty soon he will be throwing his bat at waist balls in the new Eng. league where he bellongs and the scout that picked him up must be sore at Comiskey.

Well Al they was a grate crowd out to the game and I guess we showed them we got a better game then there baby game crickit only of coarse they dident see me at my best and I would like to pitch a game for them when my old super was in shape but at that they wouldent know weather a man was good or weather he was not good and they certunly got funny idears a bout base ball and before the game wile the boys was haveing there fielding practice Evans run a bout 10 ft. and catched a fly ball and evry body beggin claping there hands and yelling so I says to mike Donlin on the bench What are they holling a bout and he says That catch and I says what was they in that catch and he says they aint use to seen a fly ball catched because when theys a fly ball hit in there crickit games there fielders is lucky if the ball dont come down on top of there head but 1 time a bout a yr. a go 1 of there crickit fielders catched a fly ball and the king declaired a leagul hollow day. So you see what kind of a game crickit is Al a baby game and I would of win that bet off them crickit players in australia if they hadent of made up there own rules and robed me out of the money.

Well Al we was just going to start the game and I was anounced to pitch and evry body beggin claping there hands and all standing up and Evans says Take off your hat so I took off my hat and bowed to them and Evans says what are you bowing for and I says Because there giveing me a hand and he says You got a grate lot of nerve because the reason there all standing up and got there hats off is because the kings just came and I told you to take your hat off because you wouldent of knowed enough if I hadent of told you and I says I guess I know enough all right and I dont half to ast you how to act or take no lessons from you and he dident say nothing back so I ast him witch was the king and he point it out a man that wasent no more king then you are Al.

So Evans wasent as smart is he thot he was and the man he point it out was may be the Lord mare or some body but who ever he was he wasent no king Geo. because he drest just like I or you and a derby hat and hadent shaved for a wk. But the king was there some wheres all right because all the papers come out today and says he was there and probily hes got a privut box some wheres where they cant none of the bugs go up and bother him and ast him this in that and pester the life out of him and the papers says they was a bout 20 thousend peopl to the game and 1 of them says theys been 5 times that many out to some of the crickit and foot ball games and ether the reporter was full of hops or else they must be a fine bunch of rummys in this burg or else they dont charge nothing to get in to there crickit and foot ball games and they certunly shouldent ought to and it would be like as if a man had to pay to set in the livry staple and watch them hitch up a horse.

Well Al I guess I shouldent ought to make no holler a bout my luck or find falt with the scarab after me geting that swell offer from the federal and whats the diffrunts weather I loose a ball game when it dont count nothing and a crowd watching you that thinks a man must be a star if he dont trip up and fall on his ear evry time theys a fly ball hit so I guess I shouldent ought to make no holler but I will be tickeled to deth when we get a way from here and on the Ship bord going home and we leave tommorow a.m. for the Liver pool where the boat leaves from and this time wear going acrost a diffrunt Ocean from the 1 we went acrost when we start it out on the trip and this is the atlantic Ocean and it dont only take 6 days to go acrost and I will be home with Florrie and little Al in a little over a wk. now and the White Sox that is the boys that dident make the trip is all ready out to Calif. on the training trip and Callahan thinks I will be going a long with him to Calif. as soon is we get to Chi but I will give him a big supprise Al and I guess I will try and get Tinker to leave me stay home a wk. or 2 insted of going south to where ever the federals is at right a way and I guess Tinker will leave me do pretty near any thing I want to on acct. of how glad he will be to have me on the club.

Well Al we been runing a round seen all the sites West Mr. Abie and the cort house and all the rest of it and beef stake diners and so 4th till wear sick in tired and that old boat cant go to fast to sute me and of coarse I wont write you nothing on the Ship bord because you wouldent no sooner get the letter then we will be back in Chi a bout the same time but may be I will write you a letter from N.Y. city if I have time. So I will cloths for now old pal.

Your Old pal.
Jack.

N.Y. city. March. 7.

Old Pal: Well Al Ive sprang it on Comiskey a bout me going with the federal and he pertended like he dident care and says he hopped I would have good luck and thats what they all say Al but you can bet he feels bad a bout it and would meet the figger of my federal contrack if Id give him a chanct but nothing doing Al because I want to be in the league where Cobb and them is in it and we will get the peopl wile the rest of them wont have no more peopl out to there grounds then if it was a.m. practice. But the federals has been keeping things quite and they aint no body a round here knows a bout Cobb and Mathewson and Johnson and them jumping to the federal and it will come like a big supprise when they spring it and I wouldent be supprised if the american and Nat. leagues busted up when they hear a bout it. They might just as well Al is try and go a long with the bunch of bushers theyll have left when the federal gets threw with them.

Well Al I sprang it on Comiskey up to the banquit tonight and the banquit was gave for us by the N.Y. fans and a crowd of Chi fans come all the way down here to meet us and they was at the banquit and there going to give an other banquit for us when we get to Chi and I called Comiskey to 1 side just before we went in to the banquit and I says Well Mr. Comiskey I got a big supprise for you and he says What is it are you going to beggin useing your head and I says No and he says well speak up.

So I told him a bout me getting a offer from the federal in Paris and he says well did you except it and I says yes and, he says Why dident you give us a chanct to meet it and I says I dident think he would want to meet it because it was 10 thousend dollars per anum and he says Well thats onet you guest right and when did your bughouse friend buy a franchize in the federal and I says I dont know nothing a bout that but Im going to play with the Chicago federal and he says what a bout the contrack you sined up with me and I says You cant expect me to play for no $2,400.00 dollars when I can get five times is much and he says All right go to the federal and good luck so I says Im sorry to leave you in the hole and he says Never mind I guess I can sell my ball pk. and live on the procedes.

So I says Will you tell Callahan and he says Why dont you tell him your self and I says I dident want to spoil the trip for him so then Comiskey says Well we wont nether 1 of us tell him and may be he will find it out for him self a long a bout the 4th of July when wear playing st Louis a double header so I ast Comiskey to shake hands to show they wasent no hard feeling on my part and then we went in and set down to the banquit and I watched him pretty clost Al and he dident in joy nothing that came off and you cant blame him and I felt bad a bout it my self but a mans got to look out for your self in this game and cant let no sentimunt enter fear with you geting the money but you cant help feeling bad when your leaveing a club in the hole and Comiskey and Callahans been figgering on a penant winner all winter and now look at them and you can bet that Comiskey will tell Callahan a bout me and not leave him to find it out for him self the 4th of July or no other time because they will half to go and get some body to take my place or that is try to. Fine chanct hey Al.

Well Al I cant hardily wait till tommorow a.m. and we get on the train for home and its after mid night now but I cant sleep on acct. of Im all exited up a bout geting home and seen little Al and Florrie again and I hope Allens tooken his wife a long to Calif. with him so as I and Florrie and little Al can have a little peace to our self wile Im home and I bet little Als talking by this time and cute as they make them and got a jaw full of teeth but may be he wont know me from a rabbit Al but he will know me before I get threw with him and after this he will remmember who I am because hes old enough now to know some thing and pretty near 9 mos. old. I wisht you could be there when he sees me Al and see how he acts when he sees his daddy and I bet he wont cry because I will make some of them comical faces at him and make him laugh even if he dont know who I am.

They was some exitemunt the last part of the trip on the boat Al and I put some thing over on these here smart alex gov. employs and when ever a boat comes in they get on the bord of it and serch evry body to see if there smugleing dimonds or perls or any thing valueble that they bought in farm countrys so of coarse if they find them things on you you got to pay your duty on them and I wouldent of knew any thing a bout it only Evans tiped me off and says I better hide that scarab or they would soke me good in plenty and I says I will keep it in my pockit and he says they will serch all threw your pockits so I says where shell I hide it then and he says Take a big chew and put the scarab in the chew and keep it in side your mouth.

So thats what I done Al and they dident never suspeck nothing and some of the rest of the gang had to come acrost and pay their duty on some of that junk they throwed there money a way on it in Cairo and japan and it dident cost me a nichol and all the wile I had some thing worth more then any of them but I come near chokeing to deth before it was all over and Demon Runyon a reporter for a N.Y. paper that met with us in Paris and made the rest of the trip from there the rest of the way a long with us says if he had of been the gov. employ that examuned me he would of put on a brown sute of cloths before he ast me any qestions.

Them fans from Chi charted a lunch and came out to meet us and the Pres. of the Boston club come out and sined Speaker up because the federal was after him and I dont know how much is the Boston club going to give him but it wont be no 10 thousend per anum and I bet he will wisht he hadent of been in such a hurry to sine up when he hears a bout I and Cobb and them.

Well they was a big parade down to the Doc to meet us and took us to the hotel and gave us a grate well come and evry body was glad to see us back safe again and we was glad to be back in the old U.S.A. where you dont half to lern no new farm languige evry 2 or 3 days and keep geting your money changed to liars and plasters and so 4th. As soon is we got to the hotel Schaefer called me to 1 side and says I must be sure and have a little poultry fixed up for the banquit so I went to my room and fixed up some thing for them Al to talk off at the banquit and heres what I give them and I wisht you could of herd them clap:

Well boys we been a round the world
All threw the diffrunt farm lands
and showed the Nat. game to
The peopl of evry land.

But wear glad to be back again boys
In the good old U.S.A.
Where they dont talk no farm Dilex
Or no baby games to play.

I pitched for Mcgraw and the giants
And give him the best I had
I win a lot of ball games but
Some times my suport was bad.

But heres to the good old U.S.A.
Where all men has = rights
Them people can have there diffrunt countrys
but me for the stars and strips.

Well Al after the banquit I says good by to Mcgraw and the rest of the boys that aint going a long to Chi with us and Mcgraw give me a box of ciggars and says he wisht he could have me a long with him all the wile and how would he get a long with out me and so 4th and I felt sorry for him and a speshuly because he dont know yet a bout Mathewson jumping to the federal and I was going to tell him a bout it and a bout me going to quite the White Sox but some body buted in and I dident get no chanct so I come out and sent a night telegram letter to Florrie that Id be home day after tommorow and now its pretty near tommorow Al and I wont have hardily any time to get some sleep before its time to get up and catch the train but I supose I can sleep on the train but of coarse if Comiskey tells Callahan a bout me jumping Callahan wont give me no chanct to sleep but will try and make me change my mind.

Well old Pal I will write and tell you all a bout little Al and how he acts when he sees me and may be I can get Florrie to take him down to Bedford and vissit with you wile Im south with the federal.

Your Pal.
Jack.

Chicago. March. 11.

Friend Al: Well Al this will be a big supprise to you Al and I bet you couldent never guess what it is so I will tell you. Im going a long with Callahan and the boys to Calif. tonight and we will get there Sat. or Sun. and join the boys that of been out there geting in shape sence last mo. and Im not going with the federal after all Al but made up my mind to stay with the White Sox. And that aint all the supprise Al and heres the rest of it Florrie and little Als out in Calif. to and they went a long with Allen and his wife when the rest of the club went last mo. and Florrie and little Als going to be there to meet me and will make the rest of the trip with me till its time to start back east and then I will send them strate threw wile I stay with the 1st team for the exhibition games or may be I can get Callahan to leave me come strate back with my famly.

Well Al I guess this is a big supprise to you and it come like a big supprise to me to I mean a bout Florrie and little Al being in Calif. and at 1st I was so sore I couldent hardily talk but Florrie showed me in her note where it was the best thing to do and insted of me not haveing no time to get aquanted with her and little Al like if she had of stayed home and been here when I come we will have pretty near 2 or 3 wks. to gather because she will be on the training trip a long with me and of coarse she dident know nothing a bout me haveing that offer from the federal or she would of stayed here and I would of probily tooken her and little Al to Skreevport where the federals is at.

Well we got in yest. a.m. and I was dissapoint it a bout Florrie not being down to the train to meet me but I went home and rung the bell to the flat and I seen the male box was full of male and bills and so 4th and no body ansered the bell and opened up the front door for me and I was going to bust my way in because I thot they must be murdered or some thing but finely the womman on the 1st floor come out and seen me and ast who was I and I told her and then she give me Florries note.

Well Al when I opened it up and seen she was in Calif. and not home I set down on the steps and blubbered and couldent read no more of her note but finely I read threw the rest of it and come to the part where she says she was doing it so as I and she and little Al wouldent half to be suppurated again so soon and then I seen what a miss take I made not telling her I was going with the federal and the rest of the letter told a bout how Allen had loned her the money to go to Calif. and I would half to pay him back the 1st pay day but I should ought to be dirty with money then because I certunly hadent throwed none a way all winter on my own fam but may be I might of spent a lot of money buying candy and beer for them farm qeens and princes.

And down to the bottun of the letter she says the lady on the 1st floor had the key to the flat and I could get in and leave some of my bagige but to not get the flat all must up and dirty and then she says an other reason why she had made up her mind to make the trip was on acct. of little Al and he was looking kind a peak it and the Dr. had told her that he was probily lonesum for his daddy and a change of seen would do him good.

Well Al for a minut I dident know what to do next but finely I thot I might is well go in and get rid of some of my bagige and see what kind of a place we was liveing in so I got the key from the lady and went in. Well Al they wasent no danger of me geting the place dirty because they was enough dirt there if a man wanted to plant corn and theyd left 1 of the lights burning and you can bet your life that Allen will pay for that and not I and Florrie and thats just what you might expect from a left hander to go a way to Calif. and leave the lights burning and I supose he was afrade it would be to dark for the roachs to read by hey Al.

Well I finely brushed some of the dirt off the phone and I was going to call up the federal and see what did they want me to do but it was 1 of these here nichol 1st phones and I dident have no nichol so I had to go clear down to the cor. of 35th st. and get a ¼ changed and I took a big shot wile I was down there and I guess I had it comeing hey Al.

So then I went back and called up the federal and of coarse Tinker was down south with the club and Weegman that owns the club was down there to and finely I got a hold of Gilmore the pres. of the league and told him who I was and ast him if Tinker had left any orders and he says no and dident act like he knowed any thing a bout me excepting the offer so I finely ast him would he wire to Tinker for me and find out what he wanted I should do and he says he would and I give him my phone No. and that was a bout 1 a clock and I dident hear nothing up to 3 a clock so I road down town and went up and seen Gilmore and he says he hadent herd nothing from Tinker but would call him up long distance for me so he got Tinker clear down to Skreevport.

And then I talked to Tinker and he says who made you a offer and I says you made me a offer wile we was in Paris and he says some body was kiding you. He says I got your cable telegram excepting the offer so evry things OK accept that we dident make you no offer and aint going to make you none because your sined up. So then I seen what kind of a gang they was Al makeing a man a offer and then line out of it so I says is that so and hung up the receiver and Gilmore ast me what was the matter and I says they wasent nothing the matter with me but I would starv to deth before I would play in a league where they make a man an offer and then try and crall out of it so I come out of his ofice and slamed the door.

What do you think of a league that trys to pull that kind of stuff and I guess Im lucky I changed my mind and come to find out they was line when they says they had Cobb and Mathewson and them and they havent got no body Al and I wouldent play in there league now for 10 thousend or ½ that amt.

So after I come out of Gilmores ofice I called up Comiskeys ofice and he was down town so they wasent nothing fer me to do but hang a round till it was time for the banquit that the Chi fans give us and as soon is Comiskey showed up there I called him to 1 side and told him and says I changed my mind and Im going to stick with your club and Callahan was standing a little ways a way from us so Comiskey hollered to him and says Cal our young friend here is going to stick with us so you wont half to get Johnson so you see Al they was going to try and get Walter Johnson if I hadent of changed my mind a bout going to the federal.

Well Al we had some banquit last night and now Im resting up and we start for Calif. tonight I and Callahan and Weaver and Scott and Benz and this here Daly and Slight and in 3 or 4 days I will see Florrie and little Al and wont half to say good by to them right after I see them like I would of if theyd of stayed here only of coarse I would probily of tooken them a long with us if Florrie really wanted to go.

Well Al I wont get no 10 thousend per anum but insted of that I will get what I been geting and besides I will half to pay for Florries fair back and 4th to Calif. and back and what ever else she has ran up on me but I guess Im lucky I dident fall for no federal league skin game and they come out and says Cobb and them had sined so theyd get me to sine but I was to smart for them and I guess may be I wont go threw that american league this yr. like gravy threw a sift.

Just a little luck is all Im asking for and I guess I will have the luck all right because I still got that little old scarab and they couldent no body get it a way from me with out I was a corps.

Im going to work easy from now till the season opens up and if Im feeling good I will make Callahan leave me open up and I will wire you a telegram a little wile a head and may be you can win a little bet on me because I wouldent give you no tip if I wasent sure what Im doing. You know me Al.

Well good by old pal and may be I will write to you from Calif. and regards to Bertha and I havent time to send you the tea I got for you wile we was in Salome but I will send it when I get back and I for got to buy some thing for Florrie and Allen and Marie so may be its a good thing they wasent none of them home when I got here but I will tell them I left there presents in the flat and then I will get some thing for them in Calif. and give it to them when wear all back home again.

But I wont get nothing for no body unlest the secy. comes acrost with some advanse money and with what I owe Allen and Mcgraw and Callahan and this in that I will be pitching a bout the 1st 2 mos. of the season for my helth but any way I been a round the world and seen all they was to see and I guess theys lots of peopl down home would change there places with me that dont never get no father from home then Terre Haute. I dont mean you Al but some of them others.

Your old Pal.
Jack.

The Courtship of T. Dorgan

Chi, May 22.

Friend Al: Well Al I suppose you seen what I done to the N.Y. bunch yesterday and when it was over Gleason called me to 1 side in the club house and says he thought it was about time I was getting the real jack so if I would bring my old contract over to the pk. today he would give me a new 1 calling for $3,000.00 per annum. So today I took my old contract over to the pk. and Gleason told me to take it up in the office and I took it up there and the old man give me my new 1 and says now go ahead and show me you are worth it. Well I will show him Al and when a man gets fair treatment from a club why you work all the harder for them.

Well Gleason told me to not say nothing to none of the other ball players about the matter as they might maybe take it in their head to hold up the club for more jack so I didn’t tell nobody only Tom Dorgan that rooms with me when we are out on the road and the best pal a man ever had and they’s no danger of him asking for more jack as he is just a 3th string catcher and all the closer he ever gets to the ball game is down in the bull pen warming up somebody but he is a regular guy and I only wished he could get in there and show them something.

Well when I told him about my new contract he said I was a lucky stiff to be getting all that jack and besides that have a beautiful wife and a couple kiddies and a nice home where all as he has got is 1 dinky little rm. over on Grand Blvd. that he can’t squeeze in or out of it without barking his ears. So I told him I said “I can’t get you no more jack old pal but the next gal that looks X eyed at me I will turn her over to you and welcome as 1 wife is about all as I can handle and then some.”

At that I would like to find him some nice gal Al as a man don’t know they are liveing till you get married and I can’t help from feeling sorry for a bird that has to go home nights after the ball game and open up the close closet and talk to his other suit.

Well when I told Florrie about me getting the $600.00 raise she asked me what would we do with it and I said I didn’t know yet and she says why not buy a car as we could have some time rideing around old Chi in a car evenings and take in the different pks. and etc. and take our friends along and show them a time. So I said “You have got a fine idear of what cars costs these days and for $600.00 you can’t even buy a tire rench.” So she begin telling me about the 2nd hand car the Dumonts which is her new pardners in the beauty parlor down town and they got it for $700.00 and its a 1917 5 passenger Peel and runs and looks like new and they must be a whole lot more bargains if a person would just get out and look for them so just to stall her I said I would keep my eyes open and if I seen a real bargain I would grab it off but what and the he‑ll is the use of us blowing our jack on a car when the Dumonts has all ready got 1 and all as we half to do is call them up and ask for the correct time and they would probably invite us out for a spin.

Personly Al I don’t see no use in anybody buying a car now as they won’t be nowheres to go after the 1 of July and besides when I am out on the road with the club Florrie would want to drive it herself and we would half to hire a steeple jack to get she and the car down off in the top of the Boston store.

Well Al I won’t half to work no more vs. the N.Y. club this serious but will probably work vs. the Washington club which comes next and he will save me for the game Walter pitchs as Walter is going pretty good now and a man has just about got to shut them out to beat him.

Your pal,
Jack.

Chi, May 27.

Friend Al: Well Al the way some people runs a ball club its a wonder we can stay in the U.S. let alone 1st place. Well yesterday Griffith started Jim Shaw against us and Gleason thought it was a good spot to try out big Lowdermilk so the 2 of them went to it but pretty soon they was both out of there and it come along the 8th inning with the Washington club a couple runs ahead and he stuck me in there to stop them and next thing you know Johnson was in there for them to try and hold the lead but we knocked his can off and beat them out.

Well of course I hadn’t no idear that Gleason would send me back at them today after the work I done so the Dumonts was out to the game with Florrie and after the game I come out and the Dumonts had a mighty sweet looking doll with them named Miss Mulvihill or something so Dumont made the remark that it was pretty dry in Chi on a Sunday so why didn’t we all hop in his car and go out to Lyons where they was plenty to eat and drink.

Well then Florrie said it didn’t seem right for Miss Mulvihill to not have no man along when her and Mrs. Dumont both had their husband so Dumont asked me if they wasn’t 1 of the ball players that was single that would like to go along. So I happened to think about Tom Dorgan so I went back in the club house and got him and you ought to seen his eyes pop out when he got a look at the Mulvihill trick. Well we went out to the car and it was the 1st time I seen it and Florrie had told me it looked like new but if it does why Jack Lapp has got a pompador. And when they said it was a 5 passenger car they meant 4 people and a weather strip.

Well the next thing was how was we going to set and Mrs. Dumont said she always set in the front seat to keep her husband from driveing to fast so that left I and Florrie and Miss Mulvihill and Tom for the soap box in back so Florrie said it looked like Miss Mulvihill would half to set on Tom’s lap. Well both partys had a hemorage to the cheek when they heard that and Miss Mulvihill said she guessed not and why didn’t Florrie set on my lap and Florrie said she had tried that to many times so any way the way we went was with Florrie and Miss Mulvihill squeezed along the side of me and Tom on my lap and I don’t know how far it is to Lyons but by the time we got there I thought we must be all of us in the Coast League.

Well we set out on the porch of the joint out there and ordered up a few drinks and everybody acted like they had came to the morgue to identify a body till finely I begin pulling some of my stuff and I wished you could of heard Miss Mulvihill split her sides only I kind of felt sorry for poor Dorgan as he acted like the cat had his tongue or something and the gal must of thought she had been pared off with Dummy Taylor. Well we had some more drinks and a chicken dinner and when the check come around Dorgan was still speechless and Dumont was danceing with Florrie so I was elected on the 1st ballad and Miss Mulvihill made the remark that I shouldn’t ought to pay for everything and just jokeing I said I was tickled to death to pay for being in her company and she blushed up like a school girl and give me a smile and I couldn’t help from feeling sorry for Dorgan but I can’t help it if that’s the way the gals feels Al and I only wished I could be just friends with them and nothing more.

Well when it come time to go home I made the remark that I wasn’t crazy about holding Tom on my lap again along with the extra load he had picked up in the mean wile so what does Miss Mulvihill do but say that if Florrie did not mind she would just as leaf set on my lap and Florrie said go ahead so that’s the way we come home and even with Dumont zig zaging all over the road and hitting her up about 12 miles per hr. all the way it didn’t seem more then 5 minutes when we come to where Miss Mulvihill lived and dropped her off and I seen her to the door and I said to her how did she like my friend Mr. Dorgan and she said “Why don’t you speak for yourself John?” How is that Al she calling me John the 1st time she ever seen me and I didn’t know they was anybody realy knew my name was John as they all been calling me Jack ever since I was a knee high grass hopper you might say.

Well when I and Florrie got home I got the silent treatmunt but she will get over it Al like they all do and anybody would think it was my fault that I wasn’t born with a hair lip or something.

But wait till I tell you what come off today. It wasn’t till pretty near 5 this a.m. when we rolled in this a.m. and I got up about 11 this a.m. and finely got over to the ball pk. and I felt like the supper dishs and finely it come time for batting practice and Gleason said you work today and I said what was he talking about as I worked yesterday and he said yes but it wasn’t only 2 innings just long enough to warm me up so I had to get in there and try and pitch and of course it had to be the day when Weaver and Collins and all of them went to he‑ll behind me and the Washington club went mad and got 4 runs which is more then they usually get all through May and Harper shut us out with 3 hits though he didn’t even have a nightgown on the ball and after the game Gleason asked me where I was last night and I told him I was out and he said yes and you are out today again to the amt. of $50.00. Well Al if he makes that fine stick I will quit baseball and go in some business where a man can get fair treatmunt and sometimes I think I better get out of baseball any way as a man that is a star in the game if he has got any looks at all why the gals all loose their nut about him and bother you to death even if you turn your back every time they look at you and a man hasn’t no business being before the public in a position where the gals can look you over and make a fool out of themself when you have got a wife and 2 kiddies.

Your pal,
Jack.

Chi, June 1.

Friend Al: Well Al I just come back from the pk. and Cleveland give us a trimming but it was about time as we win the 1st 3 we played with them. We leave for Detroit tonight and go east from there and won’t be back in old Chi till the last of the mo.

Well Al they was some excitement out in the old ball yard yesterday but beleive me it wouldn’t of never came off if I had of been in there pitching or even down there on the bench. The way that it come off was that I pitched the p.m. game Decoration Day and give them a good licking and Gleason called off the $50.00 fine he plastered on me last wk. and said I didn’t need to dress yesterday but could set up in the stand with Florrie. Well the Dumonts and Miss Mulvihill was also out to the game and we all set together and I kind of explained the game to Miss Mulvihill and I kept talking fast for the fear she would bring up something personal. Well the game wasn’t much of a game as we had them licked to death but along in the 8th inning the Cleveland bunch was sore on acct. of the way we was makeing them like it and Speaker hit a ball down towards Gandil and Chick made quite a stop of the ball and run over and stepped on the bag long before Spoke got there but Spoke was kind of sore so he slid in to the bag and that made Gandil sore and they begin barking at each other and next thing you know they was at each other and the rest of the boys was all scared and left them go to it and finely Gandil had his shirt tore off and the umps put them both off of the field. Well Al it wouldn’t of never of happened if I had of been in there as the minute Speaker had of started anything I would knocked him for a gool and it would of been good night Mr. Speaker. Just like I told Jack Graney out there on the field today I said “Speaker better not never try no monkey business like that on me or Fohl will be scarring the bushs for a new center fielder.”

Well Miss Mulvihill was setting next to me when the fight come off and I could feel her kind of tremble so I guess I must of kind of squeezed her hand and I told her to not worry because if I seen that either 1 of them was realy going to get hurt I would run down there and knock them both for a gool. So she give me a smile and made some remarks about how nice it must be to be so big and I kind of laughed it off and then I seen Florrie kind of looking at us so I cut it out.

Well the fight must of kind of went to Dumont’s bean and any way he asked us all down to the Dearborn for supper and Mrs. Dumont said we better get Tom Dorgan along so as Miss Mulvihill would have somebody to play with and she kind of made a face but didn’t say nothing so I got a hold of him and we went down there. Well Tom is a pretty fair dancer and he kept asking Miss Mulvihill to dance and of course she couldn’t say no though I guess she would of rather set at the table and talk things over but I was glad he kept her danceing at that as I was afraid things might get to personal if her and I was left at the table alone. Well finely we started home and on the way she managed to ask me where we was going to stop in Detroit and I told her so I suppose she will be sending me a post card or a night letter or something and if she does why all as I can do is just pretend like I didn’t get it. But any way we are on our way tonight Al and if we can come back from this trip in 1st place why the race is as good as win you might say as the way I and Cicotte and Williams is going they’s no club in the league can catch us in the stretch. Personly Al wile I don’t never like to leave home I am kind of glad we are going this time for Miss Mulvihill’s sakes if nothing else as the less she sees of me for a wile she will be better off.

I will write to you from Detroit or somewheres in the east.

Your pal,
Jack.

N.Y., June 5.

Friend Al: Well Al we just got in from Detroit and we played against Jennings club like we was the Red X 2nd team and if we finish up the trip like we started we will be lucky to come home in a passenger train. I suppose you read about how they beat me Al and it looks like they was enough bad breaks against me to last a whole season and the only peace of luck I had all the while we was there didn’t have nothing to do with baseball but I did happen to run acrost a bird that wants to sell a car and its a 1918 Blaine that hasn’t only been drove 4,000 miles and it looks like it was just out of the shop. I took Cracker Schalk out to see it and he said I would be a sucker to not grab it off but the bird wants $1,200.00 which is about twice as much is I figured on paying for a car so I didn’t do nothing but I kind of think he took a fancy to me and if I hold off a wile he will come down to somewheres near my price. Any way I have got his name and address and if I decide I want to pay somewheres near his price why all as I half to do is wire him.

Well Al I didn’t get no word from that little gal Miss Mulvihill wile we was in Detroit and I hope she finely got some sence in her head but speaking about Miss Mulvihill I have kind of got a idear that this here Tom Dorgan is stuck on her as whenever we get up in the rm. together that is about all as he can talk about and the day we left Detroit he asked me if I thought it would do any harm him writeing her and of course I said why no it wouldn’t and I felt like telling him it wouldn’t do no good neither one but I guess he will find that out for himself soon enough without me telling him. Only I can’t help from kind of feeling sorry for the both of them and I feel sorry for him because he has fell for a gal that has left her heart run away from her to a place where it won’t get her nothing and I feel sorry for her for looseing her nut over a man that has all ready got a wife and troubles of my own.

But Dorgan of course don’t know nothing about what has past between her and I and wile we was setting together on the train comeing east he asked me if I thought they was anything I could do to help him get in right with her. Well I told him I would do the best I could as I would like to see them both happy but between you and I Al about the only thing I could do to help his case along would be to put myself out of the way and maybe in time she would forget me but I have got Florrie and the kiddies to think of and after all a man’s family comes before your friends.

Well old pal I expect to pitch 1 of the games here and the N.Y. club is going like wild men wile we act like we was trying to see who could hit the highest foul but after the luck I had in Detroit I should ought to get some kind of luck here and all as I ask is a even break and I will make Pipp and some of the rest of them think they have got the pip eh Al?

Your pal,
Jack.

Boston, June 11.

Friend Al: Well old pal it looks like your old pal should ought to start a matrimony burro and charge a commission for fixing it up between couples that wants to get married though this time I guess the want to is all on 1 side and I am afraid my efforts is going to be waisted. I suppose you will wonder what am I talking about. Well I guess I told you about Josie Mulvihill that little queen out in Chi that Tom Dorgan went nuts over her well instead of them hitting it off why she kind of lost her noodle over me without me never looking X eyed at her and of course she is waisting her time over me as I have all ready got a wife and beleive me 1 of them is enough.

Well any way Dorgan can’t think of nothing else only she and this a.m. up in the rm. he asked me did I think they was any chance for him in that direction and of course I couldn’t come out and tell him what I realy thought so I said “Well you can’t never tell till you try.” So he says “Yes but I am a busher in the lady league and I don’t know how to go about it and if I was to ask her and she node me I wouldn’t never dast face 1 of them again.” He said “How would it be if you was to just drop her a friendily letter and kind of mention my name in it and ask her what she thinks about me and kind of give me a boost and feel her out and if she answers you back why we can come pretty close to telling if I have got a chance or have not got a chance.”

Well Al I couldn’t do nothing only say OK so I have wrote her a letter giveing Tom a boost and I am going to mail it to her special and here is what it says in it.

Dear Miss Mulvihill: Well Miss Mulvihill I suppose you will be surprised recieveing a letter from 1 who you have hardily had time to get acquainted and a specially a married man but I am writeing this in behalf of a pal of mine who I won’t half to tell you his name as you can guess who it is when I say that you have been out a couple times on partys with him which I was along at the same time with the wife and the Dumonts.

This man Miss Mulvihill has not yet win his spurrs in the big league yet and might do better if traded to another club as a young catcher breaking in has not got much of a chance on our club with a man like Ray Schalk a specially when you have got a couple of faults that a youngster has got to over come before they will make a big league catcher. I know you don’t know a whole lot about baseball and if you seen this boy stand up there behind the plate and catch you might think he was OK and as good as anybody where a man that knew baseball could tell you what was the matter with him. 1 thing wile he has got a fair arm he has got to get in a certain position to peg and looses time before he can cut the ball loose and another thing he is what we call spike shy that is when a man is comeing in to the plate it seems like he has not got the nerve to block them off but trys to stand to 1 side and tag them as they are slideing past. But this boy may overcome these faults or he might make a grand catcher for some minor league club.

Well Miss Mulvihill I and this boy has been rooming together on the road ever since the season opened and wile he don’t draw no star salery I wouldn’t ask for a better roomy and when we have a little beer or something up in the rm. I am always glad to pay for it and I feel towards him like he was a young brother that hasn’t got started yet in a money way you might say but if he keeps his eyes open and works hard he has got a chance to make good in the big league or at lease in Class A.

Now I don’t want you to feel like as if I am butting in and trying to run your fairs but this boy asked me would I put in a word for him and try and find out how he stands with you and I can say to you Miss Mulvihill that you could do a whole lot worse then give this boy a chance and wile you may not like him just at the 1st he is 1 of these birds that the more you see of him he is just the same all the wile so if he gives you a ring on the phone when we get home why it won’t hurt nothing if you make a date with him.

As for you and I personly girlie you know how matters stands with me and some times its to late to mend like in this case but a person can forget anybody if they try and we can be just good friends like I am with other girlies that is friends of my wife and all go out and have a good time together and no harm done. So if you will give this boy a chance and let by gones be by gones why it looks to me like it would be a good move both ways and remember that looks is not everything or money neither one.

With my personal regards and of course I don’t half to tell you to not let this go no father and if you can’t see your way clear why no harm done but I wished you would try and find time to write and tell me: how you feel in regards to this matter and beleive me your sinsere friend.

So that is what I wrote her Al and I signed my name and I feel like I had killed 2 birds with the same stone as she won’t make no more fuss over me and she will either give this boy a chance when he gets home or else she will tell him right off in the real where to head in at and the sooner he gets the bad news he will get over it that much sooner.

Well I suppose you seen in the paper what I done to Babe Ruth yesterday and its no wonder they call him Babe Al as I had him swinging like a baby in a cradle and the only 2 times he even fouled the ball was when Liebold run back and catched the fly ball and another time when Gandil speered that line drive off in him but he would of struck out on that ball only it was a bran new ball and I tried to curve it and it didn’t break like I intend it.

Well we leave here for Philly Friday night and after we get through with them we go to Washington and then Detroit for 1 game and then home. In the mean wile kindest regards to Bertha and don’t take no bad money.

Your pal,
Jack.

Detroit, June 22.

Friend Al: Well Al we leave in a couple hrs. for old Chi and play the Cleveland club there tomorrow and I thought I was going to work here today but I guess Gleason wanted to save me up for the Cleveland club. Well I will make them like it and maybe they won’t feel so cocky after I get done with them.

Well Al it looks like I would soon be a Barney Oldfield or something. I guess I told you that they was a bird here in Detroit that wants to sell me a 1918 Blaine car for $1,200.00 and all the boys that seen it said I was a sucker if I didn’t grab it off. Well when we got here today the 1st bird I seen was the bird that owns this car and he wanted to know if I had made up my mind or not. So I told him no I had not and he would half to give me a little more time or else cut down on the price. So he said he couldn’t do neither as he had a offer from a man here in Detroit to take it off in his hands at $1,200.00 and the man wants it right away and will pay cash and the only reason why he hadn’t sold it to him was on acct. of takeing a kind of a fancy to me and he would rather see me get it then anybody else as he felt like we was old friends on acct. of him seeing me on the ball field so often. So I said well I only had about $800.00 in the bank and I would half to talk it over with the wife 1st any way so finely he said that if I would give him a $100.00 for a option on it he would hold on to it for a wk. before he sold it to somebody else and then I could wire him if I want it or not and that will give me plenty of time to talk it over with Florrie.

Well Al it looks like such a bargain that I would be a fool to not take it and Florrie will feel the same way when I tell her about it and I have gave the bird my check for a $100.00 and if Florrie will go in with me 50 50 why I will wire the bird and tell him the deal is closed and then I will ask Gleason to leave me run over here from Chi some night and drive it back the next day and that way I won’t only loose 1 day all together and when I get that old car back in old Chi beleive me I will burn up old Michigan Ave. only they will be 1 understanding and that is that Florrie can’t drive the car neither wile I am in Chi or out on the road as I don’t trust no woman to drive a car and a specially 1 that is always looking all over the st. to see if they’s some dame that has got sporter close then her.

The bird took me out to the ball pk. this p.m. in the machine and it run like a watch charm and he asked me if I didn’t want to try and run it a wile to see how easy it run but I don’t want to take no chance of running a machine that don’t belong to me and besides it won’t take me no time to learn how to run it by myself as they’s nothing I ever tried yet that I couldn’t pick it up like childs play.

Well its pretty near train time Al and besides they isn’t much news to write. I guess I told you about me writeing to Josie Mulvihill in Chi that Tom Dorgan is nuts over her and I wrote to try and give him a boost and see how he stood with her. Well the last day we was in Washington I had a night letter from her and all as it said was “Tell Mr. Dorgan the same thing I told you once why don’t he speak for himself.” So I showed him the message and his face kind of fell and I couldn’t help from feeling sorry for him as it looks like he is barking on the wrong tree but I guess he will get over it and I hope the poor little gal will have sence enough to get over something herself as she must know they can’t be nothing only friendship between her and I and the sooner she forgets all about me so everybody will be better off.

Your pal,
Jack.

Chi, June 24.

Friend Al: Well Al from all I ever seen of Bertha I wouldn’t never accuse her from being a spend drift but beleive me she has not got nothing on Florrie. When I got back from Detroit yesterday a.m. and told her about this here car that I had took a option on it and could get it for $1,200.00 and everybody said it was a bargain and I would be a sucker to not grab it off so she said well why don’t you buy it. So I said that is all right to talk about buying it but I am about $600.00 shy and I figured that as long as I and you is both going to get the benefits out of the car you would go in with me 50 50 and pay for half of the car. So she said “All right I will pay for half of the car if you will agree that it belongs to the both of us and not just you and I can take it out and drive it when ever I feel like.” So I said nothing doing as I wouldn’t trust her to drive a lawn more let alone a car and a specially in a town like Chi where its a dull day when a 100 people don’t get bumped off in a automobile wreck.

So she said all right then nothing doing and you can either pay for the car yourself or go without it so I thought if she was going to be stubborn why I would be stubborn to as 2 could play in that game so it looks like we wouldn’t have no car as I am not going to buy no cheap 1 for no $600.00 after seen that Blaine that is worth $2,000.00 or better and the bird trying to give it to me for $1,200.00 you might say. So it looks like I would do my motoring in a 60 passenger 35th st. limousine eh Al?

Well Gleason started me vs. the Cleveland club yesterday and as usual the boys wasn’t hitting behind me and it come up to the 7th inning with the score 3 and 2 against us and we had a couple men on and 2 out and Gleason takes me out and sends Jack Collins up to hit and Coumbe made a monkey out of him and that’s the way it always goes and some day Gleason will get wise to himself and find out that I can hit as good as anybody on the club against left handers. Any way Danforth went in to finish and they got a couple more off in him and finely beat us 5 and 3.

But beleive me Al they come near being more excitement out there then just the baseball game. I was warming up before the game and Speaker come over towards our bench and I thought he was going in the club house or somewheres but he stopped along side of me and he said “Jack Graney said you wanted to see me.” So I said I hadn’t told Graney nothing of the kind so he said “Well what he said was that if I ever started anything with you Fohl would half to start scarring the bushs for a new center fielder.” So I said “I never said nothing like that Spoke and if Graney told you that he was just kidding.” So then Speaker hollered to Graney to come over and he come over and Speaker says “This big goof says he never said what you said.” So Graney says “Well he did and if he says he didn’t he is a liar.” So I said “You better not call me a liar or I will liar you all over the ball pk.” So Graney said it looked like I and him would half to settle it but Speaker said “No I will take it off in your hands.”

Well Al it was all as I could do to keep from socking the both of them and I was just going to sock Speaker when I happened to think that it would probably mean I would get put off in the field and Gleason was depending on me to work the game so I pretended like I thought they was jokeing and I said “I don’t want no trouble with neither of you 2 boys out here on the field but if you are looking for trouble I will come down to your hotel tonight and we can settle it there.” So Spoke said all right and don’t forget where we are stopping at and the clerk will give you the rm. No.

Well what they was trying to do Al was start a fight with me and get me put off the field and Gleason is up against it for pitchers and besides he didn’t have nobody else warmed up but I was to smart for them and didn’t fall for it. But beleive me if it hadn’t of been for us being up in the race and every game counts I would of socked the both of them.

Well finely the game started and the 1st ball I throwed come pretty close to Graney’s bean and he said I better not try none of that business or he would hit me with a bat so I just laughed at him and I tried to throw the next 1 at his head but the ball kind of slipped and went right in his groove and he happened to catch it just right and hit it to left field and made 2 bases. Well I got the next bird but Speaker come up and said to throw 1 at his head and see what would happen. Well I wasn’t going to leave him bluff me so I tried to get 1 close enough to scare him but I wasn’t warmed up good yet and kind of wild and I got the ball outside and he hit it down the left foul line for 2 bases and at that Jackson should ought to of held him to a single but any way Graney scored and then Liebold let a fly ball get away from him and Speaker scored and that is how they got 2 of their runs. Well Graney and Speaker tried to ride me all the p.m. but I give them back what they sent and what they was trying to do was start a scrap so as I would get suspend it but I was to foxy for them. Well Al I was going down to their hotel last night and call their bluff and knock the both of them for a gool but when I got home the baby was acting kind of croopy and I was afraid to leave the house.

Well we play Cleveland here once more tomorrow and then we go to St. Louis and I will work 1 of the games there and I will make a monkey out of them.

Tom Dorgan told me tonight that he had called up Josie Mulvihill and was going to take her out somewheres tonight to a picture or somewheres and dance and I suppose she made the date so as she could tell him once in for all that they wasn’t no chance for him and I only hope she lets him down easy as he is 1 of these silent birds that takes it mighty hard when the gals treats you rough.

Your pal,
Jack.

St. Louis, June 28.

Friend Al: Well Al it looks like I am going to be a demon motorist after all Florrie or no Florrie. I just wired a telegram to the bird in Detroit saying I would buy the Blaine for $1,200.00 if he would hold on to it for me till the 7 of July. We have got a off day in the schedule that day and I can easy get leaf from Gleason to run over to Detroit and get the old boat and drive her back to Chi and won’t even loose a day.

Well I suppose you will wonder what has happened to change my mind and if some body has gave me a birthday present of $600.00 or something. Well nothing like that old pal but still and all its going to be just the same like a birthday present and instead of the whole amt. comeing out of our family I am going to spend the $600.00 like I planned and 3 poor suckers is comeing through with the rest of it.

Well I suppose you will wonder have I went crazy or what am I talking about. Well Al I have went crazy like a fox and you will say so to when I tell you what I am going to pull off. Well they’s a bird here in St. Louis name Jack Casey that I have ran around with him ever since I been comeing here and maybe you have heard of him but any way he has got a stable of fighters and he has put on some bouts himself here in St. Louis and he knows the game from A to Z. Well he has gave me a steer on a whole lot of fights how to bet on them and I never loose a nickle yet on his dope. Well I was out with him last night and we was all over St. Louis lapping them up and we run in to a bunch of boxers and boys that is interested in the fight game and as soon is they heard who I was they popped their eyes out and said they had been a admirer of mine for a long wile and always wanted to meet me and if Jimmy Burke had a few pitchers like myself maybe the St. Louis club could get somewheres.

Well finely the talk got around to the Willard Dempsey fight in Toledo the 4 of July and I asked some of the boys how they thought it was comeing out and they all kind of stalled and said it looked pretty even and it looked like a even money bet and etc. but I could see they was stalling and finely Casey come out with it. Well Al these birds is all in a position to know and they couldn’t have nothing only the right dope and here is what they give me.

It seems like Tex Ricketts that is running the fight has spent a whole lot of jack building the arena in Toledo and he can’t expect to break better than even on the 1 fight and if Dempsey was to win why they wouldn’t be nobody left for him to fight so they are going to leave the arena up and Willard is going to get the decision in this fight and then they are going to match them up again for Labor Day and get the crowd back there a 2nd time and clean up a bunch of jack and the 2nd time they fight it will be on the level but this time the cards is all stacked for the big fellow to win and any way he is to big for this other guy to reach him. So Casey said if he was I and wanted to clean up a peace of jack why to go ahead and bet my head off on the big fellow to win this bout and they wasn’t no way I could loose unless Willard drops dead from cramps or something when they get in the ring.

Well I said I would think it over and 1 of the boys said I better not think to long as it might be to late as it is only 5 more days now before the fight and he said if I wanted to put up my jack he knew a friend of his that wasn’t on the inside and he couldn’t see nothing only Dempsey and this friend would take any bet I would make and this bird said he would see that I got the jack when I win. Well I said I didn’t want to rob no friend of his and besides I didn’t have the jack along with me to put it up and he said he would take me check but I said I would rather wait till I get to Cleveland and maybe the odds would be different and I could get some odds on the big fellow instead of even money.

Well that’s the dope Al and these birds know what they are talking about and if I was you and had a few dollars to bet why I would put it up on big Jess and not say nothing about what I have told you as the more people that knows about it why it will effect the betting.

Personly when I was through with Casey and his friends I come back to the hotel and some of the boys was still setting around the lobby in the hotel and I set down with them and told them what I had found out and Buck Weaver is 1 of these smart Alex that always knows more then anybody else so he says “Well I will tell you what I think of your dope I will take all the jack you want to bet on the big fellow.” So 1 word lead to another and I said I didn’t want to rob no pals that was on the same club with me but they kept acting smarty and finely I kind of loose my temper and I said I would bet $600.00 even money if I didn’t half to put it up and Weaver said he would take $200.00 of it and a couple more of the boys took $200.00 a peace and they covered the whole $600.00 and God help them but it will learn them not to be so smarty in the future.

So you see Al that I am going to have the big car after all and I am glad I can get it without Florrie putting in her jack as now I will own the car all myself and she won’t half nothing to say only ask me to take her rideing and when I am out on the road with the club I will have the old buggy locked up in some garage where she can’t get a hold of it and try to clime trees.

Well I made a monkey out of this club today and won’t half to work no more till we get to Cleveland where I can get another whack at Speaker and Graney and if they try any more of their smart business on me I will give them the Jess Willard only they won’t want to come back for no 2nd dose on Labor Day or no other day and speaking about Cleveland reminds me that they are going to make us go there Sunday night and play a postpone game Monday and I can’t see no sence to it only that is the last day before the country goes dry and I suppose they want us to spend it in a dry town for the fear we might enjoy ourself.

That is 1 place where poor Tom Dorgan has got it on us as Gleason has left him home this trip and he will be in old Chi the night of the 30 of June where he can get all as he wants to drink so he isn’t so unlucky after all even if the ladys don’t go nuts over him.

Well Al its time to go to bed and don’t forget what I said about betting your jack on the big fellow if you have got any to spare and in the mean wile come on you big Jessica.

Your pal,
Jack.

Chi, July 5.

Friend Al: Well Al its good night car and good night everything else and the way I feel I don’t care if school keeps or not. I am glad I didn’t advise you to bet no dough on the big fellow and if you bet some on your own hook why all as I have got to say is that I am sorry and it wasn’t my fault or them boys down to St. Louis neither one as I have knew Casey several yrs. and I know he wouldn’t give me no bad steer and the way it looks like to me is that Dempsey double crossed the big fellow and everybody else and of course only for what they told me down there I would of bet my jack on Dempsey instead of on the other fellow as in the 1st place Jess wasn’t in no shape to fight and besides when a bird 24 yrs. old fights a man pretty near 40 why its 10 to 1 he will knock him for a gool.

Well Al your old pal will do his rideing around on st. cars this summer at lease unless we win the world serious and then of course I will have enough jack to buy the finest car made and not no broke down 2nd hand Blaine and they say it costs a million dollars to run a Blaine any way as they are he‑ll on tires and the cylinders keeps getting gumed up. Well they’s 1 good thing and that is that Florrie don’t know nothing about it and if she did why I wouldn’t never hear the last of it but I am not the kind to cry over sour milk and whatever is comeing to me why I take it with a smile and go on my way. I suppose that bird in Detroit will try and hold on to the $100.00 I give him for a option but he won’t never get away with that Al and I have all ready wired him a telegram to send it back to me at once and if he don’t why the next time we hit Detroit I will knock him for a gool.

Speaking about Detroit I suppose you seen what happened in the game yesterday p.m. and when a busher like Flagstead can get to me for 3 hits why you know I am not myself.

Well Al I am to sick in tired of everything to write you much of a letter and besides they’s nothing to write about you might say only except 1 thing and that is that Tom Dorgan called me to 1 side in the club house after the game this p.m. and said to not leave till he was ready to go with me so we come down under the stand together and there was this Mulvihill dame waiting for him and grinning like a monkey and Tom couldn’t hardily talk he was so fussed up but finely it come out that they are engaged to be married and they wanted to thank me for kind of helping them fix it up and she is wearing a big diamond solitary stone that he just bought for her this a.m. and he told me on the quite that he bought it with some of the jack he win on the fight down to Toledo.

Well good luck to them Al and they can have each other as far is I am concerned and I am glad she is off in my hands as she was getting to be a kind of a pest writeing me letters and night telegrams and 1 thing another and she might of knew that a married man don’t want nothing to do with even a young gal let alone 1 that’s way up in the paints. So I say good luck to them both Al and God help them.

Well the boys on the club has began calling me Jess and I guess they think its a joke or something but 1 of these days when I ain’t feeling my best they won’t think its such a joke when they pull some of their funny stuff on me and I Jess them in the jaw.

Your pal,
Jack.